<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modal Simulation on Andre Sbrocco Figueiredo</title>
    <link>https://andresbrocco.com/tags/modal-simulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Modal Simulation on Andre Sbrocco Figueiredo</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>=&amp;copy; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://andresbrocco.com/tags/modal-simulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bachelor Thesis</title>
      <link>https://andresbrocco.com/project/bachelor-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresbrocco.com/project/bachelor-thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Steel Tongue Drum is a recently invented musical instrument that consists of
a curved and cutted steel plate. The instrument is mainly handcrafted, so by the
time of this research there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any study on its acoustic properties. For
this reason, the idea of my bachelor thesis was to propose a scientific approach
on designing this instrument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;Steel_Tongue_Drum.png&#34; alt=&#34;Steel Tongue Drum&#34; style=&#34;width:40%&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step was to understand which mechanical characteristics determines the
acoustic response. The null hypothesis was that the main factor that contributes
to its acoustic response is the metallic structure&amp;rsquo;s modes of vibration.
Therefore, I scanned the musical instrument using the software Autodesk ReCap,
that gathers photos from different angles and makes a 3d mesh out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./3d_scan_cameraPositions.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./3d_scan_mesh.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After scaling the mesh to the appropriate dimensions (using the rule placed at
the table), the mesh was imported into a CAD software (PTC Creo), and a
parametric model was drawn following the mesh geometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./3d_scan_creo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./thickness_measurement.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanical process used to conform the plate to its curved shape makes its
thickness uneven, given by the sine of the shear angle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./conforming_process.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:73%&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./conforming_thickness.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:130%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to consider that into our 3D model, we parameterize the thickness based
on the normal angle of the surface, giving the following thickness curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./normal_angle.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:80%&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./thickness_curve.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:80%&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to run a modal analysis, so I imported the parametric model
into the software Ansys Workbench and applied a fixed constraint in the contact
point of the instrument with the ground. I also refined the mesh around the
edges of each tongue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./modal_simulation_constraint.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./simulation_mesh.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of the modal simulation is the shape of each mode and its
corresponding frequency. One can observe that the first 2 modes are related to
the &amp;ldquo;free body&amp;rdquo; modes, therefore are ignored in our analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./modes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modes that have significantly more displacement on specific tongues
indicates that when hitting that tongue, that frequency will be excited. In that
manner, we can associate that frequency with the underlying tongue, giving us a
summary table relating each tongue to a specific frequency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./simulation_tongue_freq.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:25%&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the results of the simulation in hands, it&amp;rsquo;s time to perform an acoustic
test on an anechoic chamber. The base of the instrument was excited with a
mechanical actuator, and the microphone placed above the instrument recorded the
response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./test_setup_overview.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./test_setup_bottom.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./test_setup_glue.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The input was a logarithmic Sine Sweep from 100Hz to 1000Hz that took an hour
long to complete. The result can be then plotted as a Bode Diagram showing the
Frequency response Mic/Force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./bode.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:80%&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peak frequencies were then compared with the frequencies found in the modal
simulation, resulting in the comparison chart below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./chart_tong_frequencies_comparison.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width:80%&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the curves look almost exactly the same, one can cannot discard the null
hypothesis, indicating that the viscous interaction with the fluid is indeed
negligible, and the only relevant characteristics were the geometry and material
of the instrument. Therefore, the frequencies of each note of the instrument can
be approximated by a simple modal analysis, enabling one to design new
instruments with desired notes. You can take a look at
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://andresbrocco.com/files/Bachelor_Thesis.pdf&#34;&gt;full report (in portuguese)&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
